

LET'S CHAT:

Address:

Madhubani, Bihar, 847211

Phone:

+91-8076463589

Email:

atulanand.jha@gmail.com

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/atul-anand-jha/

Github:

https://github.com/Atul-Anand-Jha

Kaggle:

https://www.kaggle.com/atulanandiha/

EDUCATION:

B. TECH. - COMPUTER SCIENCE: 8.83 CGPA ITM UNIVERSITY, GWL (2015 - 2019)

SENIOR SECONDARY SCHOOL (CBSE): 79.8% JESUS & MARY ACADEMY (2014)

SECONDARY SCHOOL (CBSE): 10.0 CGPA GYAN BHARTI PUBLIC SCHOOL (2012)

Atul Anand Data Scientist | ML Engineer

SUMMARY:

Data - Driven, Self-Motivating and Hardworking individual with ~ 2 years of industrial experience in the data domain. Always fanatic for State-Of-The-Art models. I see myself contributing a vital role in R & D with Artificial Intelligence; by conjoining the magics of NLP and Computer Vision together.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Applied AI Engineer

SUMERU SOFTWARE SOLUTIONS PVT LTD DEC 2019 - PRESENT [BANGALORE]

- Major contributions to the Research & Development team.
- Implemented all AI specific modules for TalkToVideos project.
- Tested different models and finally implemented the best one NeuralCoref v3 and v4 for coref-resolution.
- · Prepared test cases for the above tasks.
- Created Asynchronous Server for deployment using TORNADO.
- Designed Voice Assistant using SNOWBOY for TalkToVideos and results casted to screen using ChromeCast.
- Debugged Chromecast API to play videos from SeekTime.
- Multiple Facial Recognition with MXNet and MTCNN.

Data Scientist & Server Assistant

LIMELIGHTIT RESEARCH PVT LTD JUL-2019 - NOV 2019 [AHMEDABAD]

- ENEROP: Completed its design and implemented its complete cloud architecture based on GCP.
- Collaborated with other developers to build a flawless clean data pipeline.
- ENTERPRISE AUTOMATION SYSTEM: handled the backend server for the project.
- · Contributed in optimizing the existing script.
- Designed the ML Based architecture for the automation of electrical Appliances based on IIOT data.

Data Science Intern

LIMELIGHTIT RESEARCH PVT LTD JAN-2019 - MAY 2019 [AHMEDABAD]

SKILLS: Machine Learning Data Analysis Deep Learning Python NLP Computer Vision Tableau Time Series Forecast Data Structures & Algorithms Linux Audacity MySQL GCP Docker C / C++

CERTIFICATIONS:

- DL Specialization (Course 1 - 3): Coursera
- DL A -Z: Udemy
- ML A z : Udemy
- Complete Data Science FOR dATA aNALYSIS (python): Udemy

LANGUAGES:



- ENEROP: Designed Cloud Architecture on GCP for data ingestion through PUB/SUB and stored into BIGQUERY and loaded into DATASTUDIO for further Data Analysis.
- Garbage Data Filtering before storing.
- Extensive Data Analysis for the Temperature and Humidity data.

Associate ML Engineer Intern

TECH MAHINDRA PVT LTD

JUL-2018 - AUG 2018 [PUNE]

- Worked on the development of Human-computer interaction CHATBOT. It was a crucial module of the VAANI: MOTOR DRIVER's Assistance System.
- Tools and Technologies used:
 - -> Natural Language Understanding (NLU)
 - -> Rasa NLU | Spacy Library | GloVe Algorithm.

PERSONAL PROJECTS:

Face Clustering [Sep-2020 - Oct 2020]

 Soccer Player's Faces Were clustered in groups and Unknown faces were filtered using the Density Based clustering algorithm DBSCAN.

>>>https://github.com/Atul-Anand-Jha/Face-Clustering

TRAVELSAATHI: Flight Trip Companion [Mar-2019 - May 2019

 An Al enabled web platform to predict Domestic Flight Ticket Prices. Track live Flight schedules and status. Can monitor Heat Index of Airport premises.

>>>https://github.com/Atul-Anand-Jha/TravelSaathi-Flight-Ticket-Price

Speaker Identification [Feb-2018 - Apr 2018]

• An intelligent speaker recognition system. Dataset created manually, can be used to test over phone tapping call records.

>>>https://github.com/Atul-Anand-Jha/Speaker-Identification-Python

CIPHER - DECIPHER (JAVA) [Apr-2017]

 Mono-alphabetic Substitution Cipher implemented in Java language and AWT technology.

>>>https://github.com/Atul-Anand-Jha/Cipher-Decipher-using-Java

ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Kaggle 1x Master and 2x Expert Top 1% rank in all three
- Top 1% Rank (53/1,347) in Airflight Prediction (ML Hackathon): MachineHack.
- Top 3.8% Rank (288/7,578) in ML Challenge #6: Hackerearth.
- Top 3 in all semesters. Rank 1 in semester IV (9.63 SCPA).
- Best Project (2017) for Cipher-Decipher written in Java.

HOBBIES:

Reading Books | Traveling | Cricket